{
    "id": "55801c1840b4454aa87f1d9d8683c525",
    "title": "Confusing Words Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She managed to keep her ……………………….. throughout the ordeal.",
            "description": "Sanity means mental health.",
            "answers": [
                "sanity",
                "sanctity",
                "serenity"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "His …………………………..  hurt her feelings.",
            "description": "Sarcasm means ridicule or taunt. Irony is a figure of speech. ",
            "answers": [
                "irony",
                "sarcasm",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………… people tend to lose friends quickly.",
            "description": "Sarcastic means contemptuous.",
            "answers": [
                "Ironic",
                "Sarcastic",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He watched his enemies turn against each other with ………………………………. amusement.",
            "description": "Sardonic means cynical. Satirical means ironically critical.",
            "answers": [
                "satirical",
                "sardonic"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The poor man received a ………………………………. beating from the thugs.",
            "description": "Savage means brutal, barbaric.",
            "answers": [
                "savage",
                "sardonic",
                "savory"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Voltaire’s Candide is a famous ……………………………….",
            "description": "Satire means comic criticism.",
            "answers": [
                "satire",
                "irony",
                "sarcasm"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The hurricane caused ……………………………….. damage.",
            "description": "Irreparable means beyond repair.",
            "answers": [
                "irrepressible",
                "irresistible",
                "irreparable"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The partners’ differences seem ………………………………..",
            "description": "Irreconcilable means unadjustable.",
            "answers": [
                "Irrefutable",
                "Irreconcilable"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………….. romantics are always falling in love.",
            "description": "Inveterate means die-hard.",
            "answers": [
                "Inveterate",
                "invertebrate",
                "invigorate"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "His ……………………………. sense of humor helped him through hard times.",
            "description": "Invincible means unconquerable.",
            "answers": [
                "invisible",
                "invincible",
                "invinsible"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The door opens ………………………….",
            "description": "Inward and inwards can be used as an adverb.",
            "answers": [
                "inward",
                "inwards",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The ………………………… train derailed.",
            "description": "Inwards cannot be used as an adjective.",
            "answers": [
                "inward",
                "inwards",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}